Abhimanyu Raizada

Software Engineer, Extramarks Noida, India +91-7837782592 | <u>abhi.raizada21@gmail.com</u>| <u>LinkedIn</u>

About

System Engineer with 2+ years of experience in Enterprise Application Development, Aspire to be an astute learner eager to accept a challenging role to make the best use of my capabilities through dedication and hardwork to move the graph of an organisation.

Skills

Languages - JavaScript, NodeJS, , HTML, CSS, SQL, MongoDB, Finacle Scripting, Git Frameworks - ReactJS, ExpressJS, Redux, Styled Components, React-Bootstrap Familiar with - Java, Python, Unix, Shell Scripting, PL SQL, CI/CD

Experience

Software Engineer, Extramarks Noida (July 2021 - Present)

Currently working on Extramarks Ed-Tech projects as a React Developer.

System Engineer, Infosys Pune (August 2019 – June 2021)

Worked on Finacle Enterprise Application Development. I have made contributions in the following

- Part of Finacle Core Banking Solution, Worked on Menu development and menu porting to 11x using React, Javascript.
- Worked on CR (Change Request) and Customization to convert Business requirements (CR) into Technical solutions. This requires UAT and Sanity Testing, Interaction with clients. Coordinating with bank IT team, troubleshooting and closing of bugs.
- Worked on E-statements Java module, sending customers statements in mails as attachments with generated transactional data.
- Worked on implementing oAuth 2.0 for finacle core application using Java, Oracle, Microsoft Azure.
- Worked on FinQuora, a MERN application for finacle developers to discuss queries and open issues amongst all the finacle teams.

System Engineer Intern, Infosys Mysore (January 2019 – May 2019)

I was trained in JAVA, Databases (Oracle), Angular 7, HTML5, CSS3 apart from Python in generic training. During my project I worked on Admin Module UI for Infosys Wingspan Platform

- Worked on building REST APIs and setting up the environment
- SPoC in a team of 7, gathered and discussed the requirements of the project with the mentor.

Projects

Chat Application Real time chat application using NodeJS, React, WebSockets

E-commerce Website Build an E-commerce Website with ReactsJS, HTML, CSS, Firebase

Education

B.Tech - Computer Science Engineering, Punjabi University, Patiala | 7 CGPA | 2019

10+2 – Punjab School Education Board | 89.4% | 2015

10 - Punjab School Education Board | 9.6CGPA | 2013